Finding Aid to the Save the Redwoods League photograph collection. 1885-2014
The Bancroft Library
- Series 1: Vertical Files., 1897-2014; cartons 1-8; A box 1; AX box 1, folders 1-20; B box 1, folders 1-15, 17-18; C box 1; D folder 1; F folder 1; H folder 1; NEG boxes 1-5; NEG(gl) boxes 1, 3, 8, 9; NNEG boxes 1-6
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Highway survey, Schoeb photographs., 1937; 3 folders (Carton 3)
    5 negatives (1 matching and 4 related) removed to NEG box 1. 29 negatives (27 matching and 2 related) removed to NNEG box 3.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Highway survey, Schoeb photographs, oversize., 1937; 1 photograph (A box 1, Folder 2)
    Englewood-Dyerville Tract showing river view of High Rock.
    1 matching negative removed to NNEG box 3.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Mather Grove. (Carton 3)
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Pacific Lumber donation to the Avenue of the Giants., July 1968 (Carton 3)
    Photo numbers Humboldt 3-01 thru 3-04.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Panoramas. (A box 1)
    Panoramas of the Eel River at the northern end of Avenue of the Giants; Logan Flats; Bull Creek Flat; bridge across the South Fork of the Eel River at Dyerville. Most are made from pieced together snapshots.
    Includes photographs by Gabriel Moulin.
    3 matching negatives removed to NEG box 1.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Pepperwood (black and white)., 1930-1977; 4 folders (Carton 3)
    Includes aerial views, Avenue of the Giants, flood damage and freeway clearing.
    Includes photographs by David Swanlund, Martin Litton, Moulin Studios and Howard King.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 18-1 thru 18-37.
    3 matching negatives removed to NEG box 1. 1 matching 8x10 negative removed to NEG box 4. p>
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Pepperwood (color)., 1964-1977, undated; 2 folders (Carton 3)
    Includes Slonaker Grove; Nicholas and Tirzah Roosevelt Grove; John Scott Douglas Memorial Grove; Newton B. Drury Grove. 10 related negatives are of Mr. Ryan's appraisal of Pepperwood Flat Area, March 1973(no prints available).
    Photo numbers Humboldt 21-01 thru 21-22.
    20 negatives (10 matching and 10 related)removed to NEG box 2.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Pepperwood townsite., March 8, 1968 (Carton 3)
    Multiple sets of aerial view photographs by David Swanlund.
    Photo numbers Humboldt16-01 thru 16-08.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Perrott-Vietor Property, Canoe Creek., 1967-1968, undated (Carton 3)
    Photographs by David Swanlund and Howard King.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 11-01 thru 11-15.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Perrott-Vietor Property, Sec. 2 and 11., 1967-1970 (Carton 3)
    Includes a hand drawn map and note by David Swanlund, and aerial views of area.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 20-01 thru 20-33.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Rockefeller Forest., 1925-1972; 2 folders (Carton 3)
    Located at Bull Creek Flat. Includes Rockefeller family and forest dedication, Standish Hickey Timber area, Calf Creek.
    Includes photographs by Moulin Studios, Newton B. Drury, and Howard King.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 4-01 thru 4-22. See also Humboldt Redwoods State Park, oversize.
    3 matching negatives removed to NEG box 1. 1 matching negative removed to NNEG box 3.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Sellars Property., March 1970 (Carton 3)
    Bird's-eye view of property including rock quarry and Pole Line Road. Photographs by Howard King. Folder contains 1 photograph.
    Photo number Humboldt 5-01.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Tryner photographs and correspondence., 1962 (Carton 3)
    Includes Bull Creek and Rockefeller Forest, signage for the areas, panoramic views and relief map of Bull Creek Basin. Photographs by James Tryner or staff.
    28 negatives (24 matching and 4 related) removed to NEG box 1.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Webb Property., 1968 (Carton 3)
    Lucille Webb Property. Snapshots taken by Lawrence C. Merriam.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 15-01 thru 15-10.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Webb Property -- Swanlund photographs., January 1971 (Carton 3)
    Lucille Webb Property. Includes aerial views. Photographs by David Swanlund.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 10-01 thru 10-11.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Weott., 1966-1969 (Carton 4)
    Includes aerial views. Includes photographs by Carto Photo Corp., Howard King and David Swanlund.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 7-01 thru 7-09.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Weott, oversize., 1966; 1 photograph (D folder 1)
    Aerial view of town and Eel River, enlarged from County Aerial photos.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Weott Groves., 1971, undated (Carton 4)
    Includes photographs by Moulin Studios and David Swanlund.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Weott townsite., March 1968 (Carton 4)
    Aerial views. Multiple sets of photographs by David Swanlund.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 6-01 thru 6-07.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- Weott townsite -- Flood., January 1974 (Carton 4)
    Includes Orin C. Scott Property. Photographs by David Swanlund.
    Photo numbers Humboldt 9-01 thru 9-29.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 21-500., 1921 (Carton 4)
    Automobile in Bolling Grove.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 31-500., 1931 (Carton 4)
    Dungan Grove. Photograph by Russell Angel. Folder contains 1 item.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 36-500., 1936 (Carton 4)
    Children's Forest. Folder contains 1 item.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 47-500., 1947 (Carton 4)
    Robinson Grove.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 48-500., 1948 (Carton 4)
    Robinson Grove. Folder contains 1 item.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 56-500., 1956 (Carton 4)
    Mailliard Grove and Charlotte Prevost Lambert Memorial Grove. Photographs by John E. Gutteridge.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 64-500., 1964 (Carton 4)
    Nicholas and Tirzah Roosevelt Grove. Photographs by Howard King.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 66-500., 1966 (Carton 4)
    Harry Chandler Memorial Grove, Rebecca Lambert Memorial Grove Addition to the Charlotte Lambert Memorial Grove, and Fanny K. Haas Grove.
    Photographs by John E. Gutteridge and David Swanlund.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 68-500., 1968 (Carton 4)
    Includes Avenue of the Giants, Helen Stanford Canfield and Marian Farr Andrews Memorial Grove, Ralph Works Chaney Memorial Redwood Grove, Helen High Daniels Grove, William J. Davis, Jr. Memorial Grove, Enoch Percy French Grove, Ethel Bancroft Richardson Grove, Marshal C. and Genevieve Fore Seagrave Grove, Harry A. Irving and Norma Irving Grove, Groves H-41, H-55, H-49.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 69-500., 1969 (Carton 4)
    Maria McKean Allen Grove and various grove signs.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 71-500., 1971 (Carton 4)
    Includes Larry and Bonnie Boisclaire Grove, Uriah T. and Cornelia T. Albee Memorial Grove, Frank and Agnes Cabot Grove, Helen High Daniels Grove, Clyde McIntyre Edmondson Grove, May and Reuben Hale Memorial Grove (Eel River at Decker Creek), Honor Grove, Harold T. and Claudia D. Stearns Grove, Smith Road Groves (H-53 and H-62), and Grove VI adjoining Maria McKean Allen Grove, Grove H-59.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 72-500., 1972 (Carton 4)
    Includes Larry and Bonnie Boisclaire Grove, Helen High Daniels Grove, Abigail M. and John S. Miller Memorial Grove, and Groves H-49 and H-62.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 74-500., 1974 (Carton 4)
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 78-500., 1978 (Carton 4)
    Includes Mrs. Neva B. Douglas Memorial Grove and Groves H-68, H-70 and H-71. Photographs by David Swanlund.
  - Humboldt Redwoods State Park -- 82-500., 1982 (Carton 4)
    Includes Mrs. Neva B. Douglas Memorial Grove, Lost Bridge Grove and Groves H-53 and H-68 and H-71. Photographs by David Swanlund.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park (Del Norte County)., 1931-1992, undated; 2 folders (Carton 4)
    Includes the Smith River; Hiouchi Bridge; Old Stage Road; Howland Hill Road; Newton B. Drury standing in a grove; Stout Grove; Ernest L. and Lou R. Adams Redwood Grove; Lincoln and Mary Louise Ellsworth Grove; Lisa Ferguson Memorial Grove; Frederick Grinnell Memorial Grove; Ruth Perry Hatton Memorial Grove; Lesley Leyson Kennedy Memorial Redwood Grove; Houston Spencer Landon and Genevieve Elizabeth Landon Grove; Mr. and Mrs. Jessie H. Metcalf Grove; Frances M. Newland Grove; Fred Somers and Helen Holton Peterson Grove; former Witt-Shaner property; Simpson Reed Grove; Frank D. Stout Memorial Grove Nickerson Ranch Trail; Howland Grade; National Tribute Grove; Groves J-23, J-24, J-25, J-27A, J-30. Also includes a letter from National Geographic regarding a photograph used for publication, and Save-the-Redwoods League Bulletin, fall 1966.
    Includes photographs by Moulin Studios, David Swanlund, Howard King, Martin Litton, Philip Hyde, Don Briggs, John Gutteridge and Mary Angle-Franzini.
    1 matching copy negative removed to NEG box 1. 3 matching negatives removed to NNEG box 3.
    - Lady Bird Johnson walking on the Mill Creek Trail after the Redwood National Park dedication., November 25, 1968; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 4)
      Front: Jack Schlotter, Area Manager of Jedediah Smith and Del Norte Redwoods State Parks. Second rank: Lady Bird Johnson and Dr. Ralph Chaney, President of Save the Redwoods League. Third rank: Rep. Don Clausen and George Hartzog, Director of National Park Service.
      World Wide Photo (AP Wire photo). This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection: From folder: Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park, oversize., 1950; 2 photographs (Ax box 1, Folder 11)
    Jedediah Smith Grove marker. Aerial view looking east in the upper Mill Creek watershed at the new Miller Lumber Company mill (number AAA 1-20-66).
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park, oversize., 1945; 2 prints (C box 1, Folder 2)
    Poster of National Tribute Grove published by the N.Y. Tribune, Inc. Illustration by Webster.
    Two copies of the same poster with variation in color.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park, oversize., February 1991; 1 map (D folder 1)
    Northern Groves map.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Boy Scout Tree Trail., 1975 (Carton 4)
    Photograph by Larry Ulrich.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Camp Lincoln Groves., 2003? (Carton 4)
    Photographs by Stephan Corley.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Cider Mills Groves., 2003? (Carton 4)
    205 matching or related 35mm negatives removed to NEG box 2.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- D.A.R. Bicentennial Grove., 1933-1977 (Carton 4)
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Freeway route (new), U.S. 199., February 8, 1964 (Carton 4)
    7 photographs by David Swanlund, and 1 map formerly housed in a notebook.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Freeway route (new), U.S. 199 -- Litton photographs., 1964; 10 photographs (Ax box 1, Folder 12)
    Photographs by Martin Litton of young people hiking through adopted freeway route in the National Tribute Forest area.
    - Adopted freeway route, National Tribute Forest, Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park., 1964; BANC PIC 2006.030--AX; 1 photograph (Ax box 1, Folder 12)
      This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Freeway Study line photos., August 1965 (Carton 4)
    Notebook type album of 15 photographs by David Swanlund taken along the Freeway Study line through Jedediah Smith Redwoods, and 1 map. Includes US 199 at Mill Creek.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Freeway Study line photos, oversize., August 1965; 3 photographs (C box 1, Folder 5)
    Photographs by David Swanlund of position D looking west, and position E looking west.
    Swanlund numbers 568 and 570 (2 copies of number 570).
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Kings Valley Road groves., 2003? (Carton 4)
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Mill Creek., 1926, 1964-2001 (Carton 4)
    Include Nickerson Ranch area.
    Includes photographs by Martin Litton, David Swanlund, Howard King and Endert (or Endest).
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Mill Creek, oversize., circa 1960, undated; 2 photographs (B box 1, Folder 6)
    Plaque in Stout Grove. Big Tree in Stout Grove, photograph by Moulin Studios (number 8864).
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Mill Creek -- Merriam photographs., February 12, 1965 (Carton 4)
    Aerial view photographs by Lawrence C. Merriam.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Mill Creek -- Paragon pictures., August 2004 (Carton 4)
    Color snapshots of the forest.
    1 related photograph of a plant removed to oversize A box.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Mill Creek -- Paragon pictures, oversize., August 2004; 1 photograph (A box 1, Folder 4)
    Color snapshots of a plant.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Rellim Lumber Company land., March 4, 1977 (Carton 4)
    Aerial views showing logging areas. Photographs by David Swanlund.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Reports -- A Report on Proposed Redwood National Park in California., 1937 (Carton 4)
    Report with photographs, submitted by John S. McLaughlin, recommending that the Mill Creek tract become a national park.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Reports -- Mill Creek Redwoods State Park., 1940-1956 (Ax box 1, Folder 13)
    Report by Clark Wing, with 6 photographs.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Simonson Property and Early Ranch., 1963-1975 (Carton 4)
    Includes aerial views.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Simpson Timber Company land not acquired in 1966., 1944-1965 (Carton 4)
    Includes correspondence and a hand drawn map of M & M lands.Includes photographs by Moulin Studios, Philip Hyde, Ken Legg and Martin Litton.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park-- Simpson Timber Company lands exchange., 1944-1956 (Carton 4)
    Includes correspondence and a hand drawn map of M & M lands. Images include Smith River, Rust Tract. Includes photographs by Moulin Studios.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Watershed -- Aerial views., 1963-1975 (Carton 4)
    Includes photographs by Martin Litton.
    See also: Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park, oversize AX.
    3 matching copy negatives removed to NEG box 1.
  - Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park -- Watershed -- Aerial views by Swanlund., 1965-1966; 3 folders (Carton 4)
  - John B. Dewitt Redwoods State Natural Reserve (Humboldt County)., 1932-1937 (Carton 4)
    Includes Whittmore Grove and county highway bridge at Whittmore Grove.
  - Johnson photographs. (Carton 4)
    Unidentified photographs by Evan Johnson.
  - Julia Pfeiffer Burns State Park (Monterey County)., September 1998-May 2004; 2 folders (Carton 4)
    Snapshots, some of which are from the same roll as Limekiln State Park photos.
    See also: Monterey County and Limekiln State Park (Monterey County)
    13 matching 35mm negatives removed to NEG box 2. Additional matching and related 35mm negatives housed Limekiln negatives in NEG box 2.
  - Julia Pfeiffer Burns State Park -- Falls., 1980-1982 (Carton 4)
    McWay Creek Falls and Partington Canyon.
  - Julia Pfeiffer Burns State Park -- 82-500., 1982 (Carton 4)
    Partington Creek in Babcock Family Grove and McWay Canyon in William Wallace Douglas Memorial Grove.
  - Kent, William., 1912, 1923 (Carton 4)
    US Congressman William Kent with John Muir at Muir Woods (modern copy print), and with Stephan Mather at Muir Woods.
    - "Naturalist John Muir and Congressman William Kent at Muir Woods National Monument.", 1912; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 4)
      This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection. From folder: Kent, William
  - King's Mountain, Skyline Boulevard, near Woodside, San Mateo County., circa 1920s? (Carton 5)
    Photographs by Lawton.
  - Klamath River and watershed., circa 1920s-1940s (Carton 4)
    Includes people fishing and Douglas Memorial Bridge.
  - Klamath River and watershed, oversize., 2 photographs (B box 1, Folder 7)
    Unprotected, privately-owned virgin-growth redwoods along the Klamath River, Sierra Club photograph. Near the Klamath, by Roger Sturtevant.
  - Klamath River and watershed -- Second Klamath Expedition., 1929; 59 negatives (Nneg box 2)
    Includes Klamath River and Little River Lumber Co. donation.
    Save-the-Redwoods League numbers 7003-7072. No prints available.
  - Knight photographs., 1926-1927, undated (Carton 4)
    Photographs by Emerson Knight of the Prairie Creek region. Includes miscellaneous printed material found with the photographs.
  - Knight photographs -- Higher values and appreciation of the redwoods, The., October-November 1938 (Carton 4)
    Preliminary study by Emerson Knight. Includes Lower Bull Creek Flat and the Redwood Highway.
  - Knight photographs -- Human values of the redwoods., July 1939; 3 folders (Carton 4)
    Original photographs by Emerson Knight. Locations include Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park and Del Norte Coast Redwoods State Park. Includes original annotated envelopes.
    194 matching and related negatives (EK-A1 to EK-Z3) removed to NNEG box 5. 21 related negatives (EK-Z4 to EK-Z24) removed to NNEG box 2.
    Duplicate prints in the form of modern contact sheets, and typewritten description are available in BANC PIC 2006.030--fALB v.9.
  - Lacks Creek area of critical environmental concern., 2004? (Carton 4)
  - Lake County., 1931, undated (Carton 4)
    Includes Clear Lake.
    Includes photograph by Gabriel Moulin.
    1 related negative of Hotaling Peninsula removed to NNEG box 2.
  - Lake Tahoe., 1953, undated (Carton 5)
    Includes aerial views of lake, Emerald Bay and Vikingsholm, and a park brochure. Photographs by J.E. Gutteridge.
    38 matching negatives removed to NEG box 1.
  - Limekiln State Park (Monterey County)., September 1998-May 2004; 2 folders (Carton 5)
    Snapshots, some of which are from the same roll as Julia Pfeiffer Burns State Park photos.
    See also: Julia Pfeiffer Burns State Park (Monterey County).
  - Little Sur River and Bixby Creek, Big Sur Coast (Monterey County)., 1920?-1983 (Carton 5)
    See also: Monterey County folder.
  - Little Sur River photographs by David Swanlund., June 1982 (Carton 5)
    Includes Granite Rock Company and Hill Ranch properties, South Fork of the Little Sur River.
  - Litton photographs., circa 1965 (Carton 5)
    Formerly housed 78 copy negatives by Martin Litton. Only photocopies of documentation (captions accompanying negatives) remain in folder.
    Matching prints for many of the negatives can be found in the vertical files under the subject/park. Example: see Logging and devastation folders.
    Negatives removed to NEG box 5.
  - Living tower, Camp Meeker., circa 1925 (Carton 5)
    1 copy negative removed to NEG box 1.
  - Logging and devastation., 1900-1978; 3 folders (Carton 5)
    Includes logging trucks, logging railroad engines and clear cut land. Most early images are copy prints.
    Includes photographs by Madison Devlin, E.R. Kirkwood, Moulin Studios, Philip Hyde, Ken Legg, J.E. Gutteridge, Martin Litton, David Swanlund, Howard King and Ansel Adams.
    6 negatives (4 matching and 2 related) removed to NEG boxes 1 and 5. 3 related negatives removed to NNEG box 2.
    - A team of oxen pulling redwood logs along a dirt road., BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 5)
      Photograph from Mendocino Historical Research, Inc. (1324-43)
      This material was selectively digitized from a larger resource or collection. From folder: Logging and devastation.
      Logging--California -- Pictorial works
    - Logging truck carrying a load of redwood logs., circa 1960s; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 5)
      Photograph by Madison Devlin, numbered 11058-12. Used in a Save the Redwoods League brochure in 1968.
    - "Near Scotia.", Adams, Ansel; BANC PIC 2006.030--PIC; 1 photograph (Carton 5)
      Numbered: 3-Cal-50.
      Landscape photographs
  - Logging and devastation, oversize., 1964, undated; 7 photographs (Ax box 1, Folder 14)
    6 photographs by Martin Litton; 1 photograph of view from east of Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park looking southwest over Elk Prairie, by Howard King.
  - Logging and devastation, oversize., 1964? (B box 1, Folder 8)
    4 Panoramas of pieced together photographs mounted on one board. Photographs by Martin Litton.
  - Logging and devastation, oversize., 1970-1974; 10 photographs (C box 1, Folders 15-19)
    Logging by Simpson Timber Company, Arcata Redwood Company and Louisiana Pacific Corporation near Redwood National Park. Photographs by David Van de Mark.
    Used for exhibit or display in 1975.
  - Logging and devastation, oversize., 9 photographs (D folders 2, 5)
    8 photographs (copies of same photo) of clear cut area, by Gabriel Moulin (number 16775). 1 matted color photograph of a man cutting a redwood tree with a chainsaw, by David H. Swanlund.
  - Logging and devastation, oversize., 1 photograph (G folder 1)
    "South Fork, California, #103 Pacific Lumber Co." Panoramic landscape of a clear cut area showing lumberjacks and railroad tracks. Photograph by E.R. Freeman, Palo Alto, Calif.
  - Logging and devastation -- Historic logging photographs from Mendocino Historic Research. (Carton 5)
    All are modern copy photographs.
  - Los Padres National Forest (Monterey, San Luis Obispo, Santa Barbara, Ventura and Kern Counties). (Carton 5)
    Color snapshots. Photographs by Ruskin Hartley.
  - Mailliard Redwoods State Natural Reserve (Mendocino County)., 1956-1964 (Carton 5)
    Includes Mailliard ranch.
    Includes photographs by Newton B. Drury.
  - Malibu Press photographs., 1963 (Carton 5)
    Logging trucks on Highway 101, and logging on private lands near Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park.
  - Martin Studio photographs., 1937 or before (Carton 5)
    Landscapes by Martin Studio, Eureka, in or near Humboldt County. Includes Redwood Highway, Bolling Grove, Fish Creek Grove, Garden Club of America Grove, Doust drive-through tree, Rolph Tree, Bull Creek Flat, Hartsook Inn, Dyerville Bridge, Weott, Eel River, and Observation Point.
    All are negatives without prints.
    21 negatives removed to NNEG box 2. 1 negative removed to NNEG box 4.
  - McDuffie, Duncan., circa 1920s-1950 (Carton 5)
    Includes snapshots and portraits of former Save-the-Redwoods League president Duncan McDuffie.
  - Mendocino County., circa 1924-1968 (Carton 5)
    Includes coast, aerial view of Anderson Valley; pygmy cypress; Orr Hot Springs; coast at Palmers Point; Union Lumber Company tree farm and redwood nursery; second growth redwood; Chandelier drive-thru tree at Underwood Park in Leggett.
    Includes photographs by Frederick of Fort Bragg and Freeman Art Co.
    2 negatives (1 matching and 1 related) removed to NEG box 1. 1 matching copy negative s removed to NNEG box 2.
  - Mendocino County, oversize., 1 photograph (B box 1, Folder 1)
    Bridges Creek area. Labeled, "Humboldt Redwoods," but in Mendocino County near Leggitt. Photograph by Russell Angel (number 5128).
  - Mendocino County, Campbell -- 03-008., 2003 (Carton 5)
    Color snapshots of unidentified people and places.
  - Mendocino County Redwoods -- Bear Gulch logging comparison., 1890-1971 (Carton 5)
    Includes Al Merrill and David T. Mason in Bear Gulch.
    Older images are modern copy prints.
  - Mendocino Headlands State Park (Mendocino County)., 1986 (Carton 5)
  - Metasequoia glyptostroboides (Dawn Redwood)., 1948-1989 (Carton 5)
    Tree at Mo-tao-chi in Central China that was worshiped as a tree god. Includes photographs taken by Dr. Ralph Chaney during his trip to China. People include Dr. Milton Silverman, Dr. Ralph Chaney, Dr. Sahni and Aubrey Drury.